<Powers>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Accuracy 1</name><Description>The character is an ace with ranged attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +1 to their Agility damage multiplier, and they gain a +1 bonus to Agility checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Agility Dmg Multiplier; 1,add:Agility Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Accuracy 2</name><Description>The character is a sharpshooter.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Accuracy 1, Rank: 2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +2 to their Agility damage multiplier, and they gain a bonus to Agility checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Agility Dmg Multiplier; 2,add:Agility Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Accuracy 3</name><Description>The character could hit a fly at one hundred paces.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Accuracy 2, Rank: 3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +3 to their Agility damage multiplier, and they gain a +3 bonus to Agility checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Agility Dmg Multiplier; 3,add:Agility Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Accuracy 4</name><Description>The character can out-target almost anyone.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Accuracy 3, Rank: 4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +4 to their Agility damage multiplier, and they gain a +4 bonus to Agility checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Agility Dmg Multiplier; 4,add:Agility Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Additional Limbs</name><Description>The character has extra limbs that can grab objects and attack foes.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character has an additional prehensile appendage (like a tail) or a symmetrical pair of them (like arms) that can be used to lift objects, use tools or otherwise take actions that normally require the use of a hand. This grants them an edge in Melee and Agility checks. A character can have as many additional limbs as they like—within reason—but they get no additional advantages for them.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Advance</name><Description>The character can advance their allies on the battlefield.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Rally on Me, Power:Scatter, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character (or an ally in line of sight) stuns or defeats an enemy.</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any allies in earshot can be affected, up to a number equal to the character's Ego defense. Each affected ally can immediately use a free movement action to move toward the enemy that triggered the reaction.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Always Ready</name><Description>The character prepared to fight.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Do This All Day, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character gains one additional reaction per round, which can be used only to activate a Martial Arts power.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Anger</name><Description>You won't like them when they're angry.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mighty 3, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is harmed by an attack.</Trigger><Cost>10 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character becomes angry and uses that anger to increase their strength. For every 10 points of Focus they spend, they add to their Melee damage bonus and lose -2 from their Logic—and subsequently their Logic defense. While using this power, they cannot use any other powers that require concentration.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Animal Bond</name><Description>The character can communicate with an animal friend.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can communicate telepathically with one animal of their choice, and they must have befriended the animal before. They cannot switch to another animal unless the animal dies, but they can select this power multiple times if desired. The communication can be verbal, visual or even more complex, such as imparting location information. There is no limit to the distance of the communication, as long as the character and the animal are in the same dimension. Animals with a telepathic bond are generally willing to communicate, even if they aren't friendly. Bonded animals often do whatever the character asks, even if it might put them in danger.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Animal Communication</name><Description>The character can communicate with a type of animal.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can communicate telepathically with one taxonomic order of animals, such as birds, mammals, fish, amphibians and so on. They can call out to them as a group up to 500 spaces per rank away, and they can communicate specifically with ones they have met or at least seen. They cannot switch to another taxonomic order, but they can select this power multiple times if desired. The communication with the animals can be verbal, visual or even more complex, such as imparting location information. There is no limit to the distance of the communication, as long as the character and the animals are in the same dimension. Friendly animals often do whatever the character asks, as long as it doesn't put them in danger—and they may be willing to risk even that for one they consider a friend. Hostile animals simply ignore all such requests, which make them a poor choice for communication.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Animated Illusion</name><Description>By manipulating visual light, the character creates a moving hologram.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Static Illusion, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character creates a visual-only illusion anywhere in line of sight, within 50 spaces. The illusion can be anything up to four sizes larger than the character, and it can move freely within its limits. The character breaks concentration if they move beyond 50 spaces from the illusion or lose line of sight to it.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic, Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Astral Form</name><Description>The character can enter the Astral Plane.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can project an avatar into the Astral Plane, leaving their physical body in a deep trance in the real world, where it is vulnerable to attack. While in the Astral Plane, they can interact with other characters in the Astral Plane, but they are intangible, invisible and generally undetectable in the real world. However, they can sense things in the real world. If the character is Rank 4 or higher, they can also take on a transparent form that can be seen in the real world. While in the Astral Plane, the character can fly, and in combat, their Flight Speed is equal to their rank times their Run Speed. Outside of combat, they can move 10 times as fast.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Attack Stance</name><Description>The character enters an aggressive attack stance, ready to strike in any direction.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character doubles their Melee ability bonus to damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts,  Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Banging Heads</name><Description>The character takes two nearby enemies and slams their heads into each other.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes one Melee check against the Melee defense scores of two enemies within reach. If the attack fails against either foe, it fails entirely. If the attack is a success against both foes, each enemy takes full damage. On a Fantastic success, each enemy is also knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Battle Plan</name><Description>The character always has a plan.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Inspiration, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character inspires one or more allies of their choice in earshot, up to the character's Vigilance. Inspired allies gain an edge on all action checks until the start of the character's next turn.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Blazing-Fast Fists</name><Description>The character can attack superfast.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character has an edge on all Melee attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Blink</name><Description>The character teleports a short distance away.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, movement or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked.</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character teleports into a clear space they can see or have been to, up to their rank in spaces away. If someone was about to attack them and they are now out of reach or line of sight, the attack automatically fails. If they are still within reach or line of sight, the attack has trouble instead.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Combat Teleport Speed;Rank,replace:Teleport Speed;Rank</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Blink Barrage</name><Description>The character teleports rapidly around an opponent.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Blink, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character teleports several times in quick succession and winds up in a clear space they can see or have been to, up to their rank in spaces away. Any attacks have trouble against them for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Blink Defense</name><Description>The character teleports a short distance away.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Blink, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character or an ally within reach is the subject of a ranged attack.</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character pops away just as the attack reaches them and then pops back into the same space, leaving the projectile behind. The character makes an Ego check with an edge against the attacker's Agility check result. On a success, the projectile from the attack is teleported away, someplace safe. On a Fantastic success, the attack is turned against the attacker, using the Ego check the character just made as the attack check.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Blur</name><Description>The character moves like a blur!</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 2, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any attacks against the character have trouble.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Body Sheet</name><Description>The character can flatten themselves like a sheet.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flexible Bones 2, Power:Extended Reach 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character falls or is the target of an attack.</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character gains Health Damage Reduction 3, but they cannot make attacks. They gain a Glide Speed equal to double their Run Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Glide Speed;2 x Combat Run Speed,calc:Glide Speed;2 x Combat Run Speed. replace:Health Dmg Reduction;3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Body Sphere</name><Description>The character can form their body into a protective sphere.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Body Sheet, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character or an ally is the target of an attack.</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character forms their body into a sphere, protecting up to one ally per rank squeezed into the same space. Those inside the sphere gain Health Damage Reduction 3 against outside attacks, but they cannot move on their own until the character releases them. Alternatively, if the attacker is within the character's reach, the character can make an Agility check against the target’s Agility defense. On a success, the character envelops the attacker, grabbing them. On a Fantastic success, the character closes the sphere enough to pin the attacker too.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Bolts of Balthakk</name><Description>The character fires enchanted bolts of electricity from their fingers.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>20 spaces</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego check with an edge against the Agility defense of a target in their line of sight. For this attack, add +1 to the character's Agility damage bonus for every 2 points of Focus they spend. On a success, an affected target takes that total damage. On a Fantastic success, an affected target takes double that total damage and is stunned for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Boost Powers</name><Description>The character turbocharges another character's powers!</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Bump Power, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character picks one character within 5 spaces and boosts all of their powers. If the powers have ranges or effective areas or durations, these are doubled. If the powers affect a damage multiplier, add 1 to the effects. Any effects that normally happen with a Fantastic success automatically happen on any success, not just a Fantastic one. If the target's powers have costs, the character must pay the highest of them or a minimum of 15 Focus.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Borrow Senses</name><Description>The character can use another person's senses.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can use the full senses of someone or something with whom they have established a telepathic link. While they do, they retain the use of their own too.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Bounce Back</name><Description>The character bounces back from even the hardest falls.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flexible Bones 1, Power:Slip Free, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>The character takes damage from a fall or is knocked prone.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The fall doesn't damage the character. If they are prone, they stand up. If they'd like, they can also jump a number of spaces up to their Run Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts, Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Brace for Impact</name><Description>The character mentally toughens themselves for a fight.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Do This All Day, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>An enemy deals physical damage to the character.</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>For every point of Focus spent, the character can ignore 1 point of Health damage dealt by the attack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Brain Drain</name><Description>The character consumes the energies of another.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The target is grabbed.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego attack against the target's Vigilance. If it succeeds, the target takes regular Focus damage, and the character heals half that much Focus for themselves. On a Fantastic success, the character heals their full Focus damage instead.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Brawling</name><Description>The character has the moves and is hard to hit.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can use their Melee defense score against Agility attacks too.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Agility Defence Score;Melee Defence Score</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Brilliance 1</name><Description>The character puts their brain to work.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +1 to their Logic damage multiplier, and they gain a bonus to Logic checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Logic Dmg Multiplier;1,add:Logic Non-Combant Check:1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Brilliance 2</name><Description>Everything makes more sense to the character.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Brilliance 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +2 to their Logic damage multiplier, and they gain a +2 bonus to Logic checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Logic Dmg Multiplier;2,add:Logic Non-Combant Check:1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Brilliance 3</name><Description>Little can stop the character's mind.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Brilliance 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +3 to their Logic damage multiplier, and they gain a +3 bonus to Logic checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Logic Dmg Multiplier;3,add:Logic Non-Combant Check:1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Brilliance 4</name><Description>The character's intelligence is unparalleled.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Brilliance 3, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +4 to their Logic damage multiplier, and they gain a bonus to Logic checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Logic Dmg Multiplier;4,add:Logic Non-Combant Check:1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Bump Power</name><Description>The character bumps up another character's power.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character picks one power from another character within 5 spaces and boosts it. If the power has ranges or effective areas or durations, these are doubled. If the power affects a damage multiplier, add 1 to the effect. Any effects that normally happen with a Fantastic success automatically happen on any success, not just a Fantastic one. If the power has a cost, the character must pay it as well, with a minimum of 5 Focus.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Catch Bullets</name><Description>The character is fast enough to catch bullets—safely!</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>A ranged attack using physical projectiles (arrows, bullets, etc.) is made against the character or a character within their reach.</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Agility check, using the attacker's attack result as the target number. If the check succeeds, the attack is nullified. On a Fantastic success, the character gets their reaction back.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Chain Strikes</name><Description>The character unleashes a hail of strikes.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Fast Strikes, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes a close attack with an edge. If the attack is a success, the enemy takes regular damage. On a Fantastic success, the character can also make an additional Chain Strike.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Change Of Plans</name><Description>The character thinks of a better way.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Inspiration, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>An ally has trouble on an action check.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The ally gains an edge on that action check.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Cloak</name><Description>The character makes people believe they're not there.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character uses a mirage to block their presence from the minds of people within 20 spaces per rank. Cameras can still record them, but anyone looking in the character's direction sees nothing. The target number for anyone trying to detect the character is the character's Logic defense.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Cloak Group</name><Description>The character mentally hides themselves and their friends.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Cloak, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Using a mirage, the character blocks their presence—and the presence of up to one other person per rank, within 10 spaces—from the minds of people within 20 spaces per rank. Cameras can still record them, but anyone looking in the characters' direction sees nothing. The target number for anyone trying to detect the character or the others protected is the character's Logic defense.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Clobber</name><Description>The character pummels their foe with enough force to knock them flat.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes a close attack against an enemy. If the attack is a success, the enemy takes regular damage. On a Fantastic success, the enemy takes double damage and is knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Clone Moves</name><Description>The character duplicates another character's combat moves.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character picks another character within 10 spaces and in their line of sight and duplicates all their powers that could be selected with the Special Training origin. They can now use those powers as if they were always theirs. If the copied powers have costs, the character must pay the highest of them, or a minimum of 5 Focus. When the character uses a copied power, they must pay any cost normally as well.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Clone Powers</name><Description>The character duplicates all of another character's powers.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Copy Power, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character picks another character within 10 spaces and duplicates all of their powers. They can now use those powers as if they were always theirs. If the target's powers have costs, the character must pay the highest of them, or a minimum of 15 Focus. When the character uses a copied power, they must pay any cost normally as well.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Coiling Crush</name><Description>The character wraps around a target and crushes it.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Extended Reach 1, Power:Reverse Punch, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character grabs an enemy.</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes a Melee attack. On a success, the enemy is paralyzed. On a Fantastic success, the enemy also takes regular damage. During the character's subsequent turns, they can spend their movement action to make a Melee check against the enemy's Resilience. If this succeeds, they inflict regular Health damage. On a Fantastic success, they do double damage instead. During the paralyzed enemy's turn, they can make a Melee check against the character's Melee defense to break free.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Combat Support</name><Description>The character gives a friend a hand.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Change Of Plans, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Once per battle, the character chooses an ally in earshot. If the ally makes an action check before the start of the character's next turn, the ally automatically rolls a 1 on their Marvel die, and that die cannot be affected by trouble.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Combat Trickery</name><Description>The character is a tricky one!</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character makes an attack.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Once per battle, when the character is attacking targets of equal or higher rank, the character automatically rolls a 1 on their Marvel die, and that die cannot be affected by trouble. If attacking multiple targets, all must be of equal or higher rank.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Command</name><Description>The character forces someone to follow an order.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character gives an order to a target with whom they've established a Telepathic Link. The character makes a Logic check against the target's Logic defense. On a success, the target complies. On a Fantastic success, the character gains an edge the next time they use this power against this same target. Orders must be single-action. Harmful orders incur trouble, self-harm doubles trouble.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Control Fog</name><Description>The character can create or dispel a thick fog.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character creates a thick fog for up to 50 spaces per rank around them that blocks all line of sight beyond 10 spaces. They can also dispel any fog in a similar area.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Control Weather</name><Description>The character can make it rain.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>It starts to rain in an area up to 5 miles across times the character's rank, centered on the character. All ranges are cut in half. Movement is not affected.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Control Weather 2</name><Description>The character can make it storm.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Control Weather 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>It starts to storm in an area up to 5 miles across times the character's rank, centered on the character. All ranges and speeds are cut in half.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Control Weather 3</name><Description>The character creates a thunderstorm.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Control Weather 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>It starts to storm in an area up to 5 miles across times the character's rank, centered on the character. All ranges and speeds are cut in half. If the character also has Elemental Blast (Electricity), they can use it as a reaction when attacked while this power is active.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Control Weather 4</name><Description>The character generates a hurricane.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Control Weather 3, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>It starts to storm in an area up to 5 miles across times the character's rank, centered on the character. All ranges and speeds are cut to one quarter normal, and flying is impossible. If the character has Elemental Barrage (Electricity), they can use it as a reaction when attacked while this power is active.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Dimensional Portal</name><Description>The character opens a portal to another place.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Dimensional Travel Together, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character opens a glowing portal in a space next to them that moves anything that enters it between that space and its destination, which forms a matched glowing portal in the other place. The other end of the portal must be in a clear space in another dimension that the character has been to. Anything can move through the portal in either direction until it is closed, which the character can do at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Dimensional Travel</name><Description>The character moves from one dimension to another.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character instantly moves from their current dimension to another dimension within the same universe. For instance, from Earth to Asgard, Limbo, or K'un-Lun. When they move to the other dimension, they can arrive in any place they've been to before. Otherwise, they arrive at the most common entrance to that dimension.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Dimensional Travel Other</name><Description>The character sends someone to another dimension.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Dimensional Travel, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The target is grabbed.</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego check against the Vigilance defense of a target they have grabbed. On a success, the character can send the target to another dimension. The target can be sent to any location in that dimension that the character has been to before. Otherwise, the target arrives at the most common entrance to that dimension.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Dimensional Travel Together</name><Description>The character brings someone with them to another dimension.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Dimensional Travel, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The target is grabbed.</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character moves to a different dimension, taking any person they are touching with them. If the target does not wish to come along, the character must grab them first. When they move to the other dimension, they can arrive in any place they've been to before. Otherwise, they arrive at the most common entrance to that dimension.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Discipline 1</name><Description>The character works to hone their power.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +1 to their Ego damage multiplier and they gain a bonus to Ego checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Ego Dmg Multiplier;1, add:Ego Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Discipline 2</name><Description>The character is more in touch with their power than ever.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Discipline 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +2 to their Ego damage multiplier, and they gain a bonus to Ego checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Ego Dmg Multiplier;2, add:Ego Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Discipline 3</name><Description>Few can top the character's grasp on their power.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Discipline 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +3 to their Ego damage multiplier, and they gain a +3 bonus to Ego checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Ego Dmg Multiplier;3, add:Ego Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Discipline 4</name><Description>The character has mastered their power.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Discipline 3, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character adds +4 to their Ego damage multiplier, and they gain a bonus to Ego checks other than attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Ego Dmg Multiplier;4, add:Ego Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Disguise</name><Description>The character appears to be someone else.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character instantly alters their appearance so that they appear to be someone else. The target number for anyone trying to see through the disguise is the character's Ego defense. If the character is impersonating someone known to the other person, that person has an edge.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Dispel Spell</name><Description>The character puts an end to a foe's magic.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego check against the Ego defense of a target using a magic power that requires concentration. On a success, the target's concentration on that power is broken. On a Fantastic success, the target's concentration is broken entirely.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Disrupt Electronics</name><Description>The character can scramble electronics by moving through them.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>When phasing through electronics, the character can scramble them, causing them to either shut down or crash. In the case of powers that are Tech Reliant (and feature electronics), they are unusable for 1 turn while they reboot.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Disrupt Nerves</name><Description>The character can scramble someone's nervous system.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>When phasing through a person, the character can attempt to scramble their nervous system. The character makes an Ego check against the target's Resilience defense. On a success, the target is stunned for one round. On a Fantastic success, the target also falls prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Disrupt Person</name><Description>The character can hurt someone with their phasing powers.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character becomes slightly solid while phasing themselves or a phased weapon through someone. They make a close attack. On a success, the attack does normal damage, ignoring any Health Damage Reduction. On a Fantastic success, the attack does double damage instead, ignoring any Health Damage Reduction, and the target is stunned for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts, Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Do This All Day</name><Description>The character draws on their inner strength to heal themselves.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character heals 2 points of Health for every point of Focus they spend.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Domination</name><Description>The character forces someone to follow their orders—permanently.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Orders, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character dominates a target with whom they've established a Telepathic Link and who has no Focus left. The character makes a Logic check with trouble against the target's Logic defense. On a success, the target is completely dominated and will follow the character's orders. On a Fantastic success, the character gains an edge the next time they use this power against the same target. The result of the check is the target number for any attempts by the target to end the domination. Harmful orders give the target a Logic check, Heroic targets get an edge, and self-harm doubles the edge.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Double Tap</name><Description>To be twice as sure.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes a ranged attack against an enemy within 2 spaces. On a success, the enemy takes regular damage. On a Fantastic success, the enemy takes double damage and is bleeding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Edit Memory</name><Description>The character alters someone's memory.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Memory Blip, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character alters the memory of a target with whom they've established a Telepathic Link. This can range from erasing a chunk of memory to implanting entirely new memories. The Narrator sets the target number based on complexity. The character makes a Logic check against the target's Logic defense. On a success, the memories are altered. On a Fantastic success, the target has trouble on checks to refute such memories in the future. If the target doubts the edited memory, they can make a Logic check to recover original memories. On success, they remember both versions; on Fantastic success, they know who did it.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Barrage</name><Description>The character hurls a barrage of their element at their foes.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Blast, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character designates a space within their line of sight. The attack can affect every enemy within 10 spaces of that point. The character makes a single Ego check and compares it to each target's Resilience defense. Affected enemies take half regular damage. On a Fantastic success, they take full regular damage and the elemental type's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Barrier</name><Description>The character forms a wall of their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Blast, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character forms a wall of their element within line of sight and up to 10 spaces per rank away. It covers up to 2 spaces across per rank. The character makes an Agility check against targets in affected spaces. On a success, the character chooses the side the target ends up on. On a failure, the target chooses. On a Fantastic success, the target suffers the element's special effect. Attacks against the barrier are against the character's Ego defense. Attacks ≤10 damage are absorbed; >10 damage destroy the barrier, leaving those behind unharmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Blast</name><Description>The character blasts a foe with their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Burst, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 or more Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>The character makes a ranged attack with an edge at an enemy in line of sight. Add +1 to Agility damage bonus for every 2 points of Focus spent. On success, the target takes that total damage. On a Fantastic success, the target takes double damage and suffers the elemental type's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Burst</name><Description>The character fires a burst of their element.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>The character makes a ranged attack against an enemy in line of sight. On success, it inflicts regular damage. On a Fantastic success, the enemy takes double damage and the elemental type's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Form</name><Description>The character's body is made of their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Reinforcement, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character's body is entirely made of their element, giving them a steady supply to use and making them essentially unkillable. When they lose all Health, the form loses cohesion and falls apart. At ≥1 Health, they can reform. To use the elemental body in unusual ways, pick Plasticity powers. To be fully human at times, pick Shape-Shift.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Grab</name><Description>The character uses their element to snare a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Burst, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>Varies</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego attack against a target's Melee defense within 5 spaces times the character's rank. On a success, the character grabs the target with their element. On a Fantastic success, the target can also be pinned and suffers the element's special effect. Breaking free requires a successful Melee check against target number 20.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Infusion</name><Description>The character infuses a weapon with their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Burst, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character infuses their energy into a handheld weapon in their grasp. When the character gets a Fantastic attack with the weapon, add the energy's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Prison</name><Description>The character can create a cage of their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>Same as the character's Elemental Protection power</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character picks a point within their line of sight and traps chosen targets within up to 5 spaces times their rank in a prison of their element. The character makes an Ego check against targets' Agility defense. On each success, the target is trapped. On a Fantastic success, imprisoned people suffer full damage and the element's special effect. Attacks against the prison are absorbed as if against Elemental Protection; if damage exceeds the protection, the prison is destroyed but no one inside is harmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Protection</name><Description>The character protects themselves with their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Barrier, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked or otherwise in danger</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any attacks against the character that do 10 points of damage or less are absorbed; protection continues. If an attack does more than 10 points of damage, it destroys the protection. The character remains unharmed either way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Protection 2</name><Description>The character's elemental protection is like armor.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked or otherwise in danger</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any attacks against the character that do 20 points of damage or less are absorbed; protection continues. If an attack does more than 20 points of damage, it destroys the protection. The character remains unharmed either way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Protection 3</name><Description>The character's elemental protection is like a tank.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked or otherwise in danger</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any attacks against the character that do 30 points of damage or less are absorbed; protection continues. If an attack does more than 30 points of damage, it destroys the protection. The character remains unharmed either way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Protection 4</name><Description>The character's elemental protection is like a fortress.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 3, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked or otherwise in danger</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Any attacks against the character that do 40 points of damage or less are absorbed; protection continues. If an attack does more than 40 points of damage, it destroys the protection. The character remains unharmed either way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Push</name><Description>The character can move a target with their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Burst, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego attack against the target's Agility defense. On a success, the character can move the target in any direction, up to 1 space times the character's rank. On a Fantastic success, the target also takes regular damage, is knocked prone, and suffers the element's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Reinforcement</name><Description>The character reinforces their powers with their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Damage gets through an elemental power</Trigger><Cost>Varies</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can transfer any Health damage that gets through an elemental power that grants damage protection to their Focus instead, leaving the protection intact.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Ricochet</name><Description>The character bounces the burst off one foe and into another.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Burst, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces times the character's rank</Range><Effect>The character makes a ranged attack against a target in line of sight. On a success, it inflicts regular damage. On a Fantastic success, energy bounces to another target in line of sight, allowing a new attack with added range. This repeats until an attack is not Fantastic.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Sphere</name><Description>The character can create a protective sphere of their element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Protection 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>Same as the character's Elemental Protection power</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character envelops themselves—and any chosen people within up to 5 spaces times their rank—in a protective sphere of their element. Ego check against Agility defense of unwanted characters allows moving them outside. On a Fantastic success, moved people take full damage and the element's special effect. Attacks against the sphere are absorbed as Elemental Protection. If damage exceeds protection, the sphere is destroyed but no one inside is harmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Elemental Suffocation</name><Description>The character envelops a target's head in an element.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Grab, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>The target is grabbed with Elemental Grab</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>Varies</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego attack against the grabbed target's Resilience defense. On a success, the target takes regular damage. On a Fantastic success, the target can also be pinned and suffers the element's special effect. With unsuitable elements, this power chokes the target instead.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Energy Absorption</name><Description>The character turns damage into power.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>The character takes Health damage</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can take any Health damage (after reduction), ignore it, and add that number to Focus instead, up to double maximum. Extra Focus fades after combat.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Environmental Protection</name><Description>Environmental effects don't bother the character.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character is unharmed by intense cold or heat, deep-sea pressure, or the radiation and vacuum of space. The player can select any combination of protections that fits the character concept.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>ESP</name><Description>The character can sense the presence of others.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can sense the presence of others within 100 spaces per rank, learning their location and general status. Can detect super-powers. Targets attempting to remain undetected require Logic checks against their Vigilance. Fantastic success also identifies the source of powers.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Evasion</name><Description>The character can twist or dodge quickly.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can use their Agility defense score against Melee attacks as well.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Melee Defence Score;Agility Defence Score</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Exorcism</name><Description>The character removes an intruder from someone's body.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes an Ego check against a possessor's Ego defense. On success, the possessor's concentration is broken, ending the possession. On a Fantastic success, all of the possessor's concentrations are broken, and the possessor is stunned for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Exploit</name><Description>The character finds a weak spot and exploits it.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Vicious Attack, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>A Fantastic success on an attack using the character's weapon that deals at least 1 point of damage</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character makes a Melee attack against the target's Resilience defense. On success, the damage ignores Health Damage Reduction. On a Fantastic success, the target suffers double damage and the weapon's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Extend Invisibility</name><Description>Extends the duration of Invisibility beyond its normal limits.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Invisibility</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Makes one person or object within reach invisible. Can be one size bigger than the character per rank.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Extended Reach 1</name><Description>Increases the reach of melee attacks slightly.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character's reach quadruples.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Extended Reach 2</name><Description>Further increases the reach of melee attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Extended Reach 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character's reach is 10 times normal.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Fast Attacks</name><Description>Grants bonus edge when making multiple attacks in a turn.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Splits attack to make two close attacks against separate targets within reach, or focus on one. Make a single Melee check. Success: half damage; Fantastic success: full damage and bonus attack against any target within reach.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Fast Hands</name><Description>Allows quick manipulation of objects or tools.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Point-blank Parry, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Gain one additional reaction per round, usable only to trigger a Ranged Weapons power.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Fast Strikes</name><Description>Improves the speed of striking actions, giving edge on attack rolls.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Splits attack to make two close attacks against separate targets within reach, or focus on one. Make one Melee check. Success: half damage; Fantastic success: full damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Flames of the Faltine</name><Description>Generates intense magical flames from the Faltine, causing damage to enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>Ego attack against Agility defense of a target in line of sight. Success: regular damage; Fantastic success: double damage and 5 points of ongoing damage each round until extinguished.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Flare</name><Description>Emits a bright burst of light, potentially blinding foes.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Illumination, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack vs Vigilance of all enemies within 5 spaces. Success: blinded for one turn; Fantastic success: also takes regular damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Flexible Bones 1</name><Description>Bones are more pliable, reducing injury from falls or blunt trauma.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 1. Edge on Agility checks for contortion and escape.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Flexible Bones 2</name><Description>Further reduces damage from impacts, allowing more extreme contortions.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flexible Bones 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 2. Double edge on Agility checks for contortion and escape.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;2</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Flexible Fingers</name><Description>Increases manual dexterity for delicate tasks.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>With a Standard action, automatically pick any lock or shape hands into almost any simple tool.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Flight 1</name><Description>Grants the ability to fly at a basic level.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Combat Flight Speed = Rank × Run Speed. Outside combat: move 3× Flight Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Flight Speed;Rank x Run Speed, calc:Flight Speed;Rank x Run Speed x 3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Flight 2</name><Description>Improves flying speed and maneuverability.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flight 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Outside combat: fly up to 50× Flight Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Flight Speed; Combat Flight Speed x 50</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Flying Double Kick</name><Description>Allows a kick while airborne, with extra damage or edge.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Leg Sweep, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack against two enemies within reach. Success: regular damage; Fantastic success: double damage and knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Focus Fire</name><Description>Targets a single enemy with coordinated attacks, increasing damage or accuracy.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Battle Plan, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Calls out an enemy in line of sight. Allies of choice in earshot gain an edge on all action checks against that enemy.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Focused Fury</name><Description>Grants a bonus when attacking the same target repeatedly.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Exploit, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack with edge. Add +1 to Melee damage for every 2 Focus spent. Success: total damage; Fantastic success: double total damage and weapon special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Focused Strike</name><Description>A precise attack that ignores some defenses.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Chain Strikes, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack. Add +1 to Melee damage for every 2 Focus spent. Success: total damage; Fantastic success: double total damage and target stunned for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Fool</name><Description>Imposes disadvantage on opponents’ perception or attacks through trickery.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Alters appearance in minds of anyone within 20 spaces per rank. Cameras see normally. Target number to see through illusion = Logic defense. Known targets: edge applied.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Furious Attacks</name><Description>Increases damage output when enraged.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Whirling Frenzy, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Split attack against two targets within reach or focus on one. Add +1 to Melee damage for every 2 Focus spent. Success: half total damage; Fantastic success: full total damage and weapon's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Grand Mirage</name><Description>Creates a large-scale illusion affecting multiple targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mirage, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Creates a full-sensory mirage affecting everyone in a Telepathic Network in the same locale. Mirage can move freely.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Grand Fool</name><Description>An enhanced version of Fool affecting a wider area.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Fool, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Alters appearance of self and up to one other person per rank within 10 spaces. Target number to see through illusion = Logic defense. Known targets: edge applied.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Grand Illusion</name><Description>A powerful illusion that can deceive multiple senses over a wide area.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Animated Illusion, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>50 spaces</Range><Effect>Creates a sound and sight illusion anywhere in line of sight, up to 5 sizes larger than the character. Can move freely within limits. Breaks concentration if character moves beyond 50 spaces or loses line of sight.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Grappling Technique</name><Description>Grants edge on grapple or hold maneuvers.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack. Success: target takes regular damage and is grabbed; Fantastic success: double damage and pinned.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Ground-Shaking Stomp</name><Description>A stomp that can knock down or damage nearby opponents.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Smash, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Melee check vs Agility of all targets within reach + rank in spaces. Success: half regular damage; Fantastic success: full damage and knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Group Flight</name><Description>Allows multiple allies to fly together under coordinated control.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flight 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>For each point of Ego, can carry one ally into the air. Flight Speed of group is half character's. Allies must remain within 5 spaces × rank. Can release any/all allies at any time.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Group Invisibility</name><Description>Makes a group of allies invisible simultaneously.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Extend Invisibility, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>For each point of Ego, make one person/object invisible, including self. Each can be one size bigger than the character per rank.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Group Levitation</name><Description>Allows multiple targets to levitate at once.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Levitation, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Move up to one person per rank through air in any direction at Run Speed. Targets must remain within 5 spaces × rank. If target resists, must be grabbed first.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Grow 1</name><Description>Slightly increases the size and strength of the character.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Can grow up to Huge size. Can return to normal size at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Grow 2</name><Description>Further increases size and strength.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Can grow up to Gigantic size. Can return to normal size at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Grow 3</name><Description>Significantly increases size and strength.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Can grow up to the size of a house. Can return to normal size at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Grow 4</name><Description>Maximizes size and strength growth.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Can grow up to Gargantuan size. Can return to normal size at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Growing Attack</name><Description>Attacks become stronger as the character grows.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Grows</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack with an edge. Success: damage for size being grown to; Fantastic success: double damage and target stunned.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Headshot</name><Description>Aimed attack targeting the head with increased damage or critical chance.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Stopping Power, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ranged attack on enemy. Success: double damage; Fantastic: triple damage. Any damage also stuns target one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Healing Factor</name><Description>Grants rapid regeneration of wounds over time.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>At end of turn, regain Health equal to Resilience. Works outside combat too.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Heightened Senses</name><Description>Improves perception, allowing edge on detection and awareness checks.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Senses twice as far as normal. Edge on Vigilance checks to perceive. Enemies have trouble sneaking past.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Heightened Senses 2</name><Description>Further enhances perception, detecting more subtle cues.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Heightened Senses 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character can sense things roughly four times as far as normal. They can compensate for lost senses (e.g., if blinded or deafened), listen to heartbeats to detect lying (not 100% reliable), have double edge on Vigilance checks, and enemies have double trouble on sneaking checks.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Hellfire Chains</name><Description>Conjures chains of mystical fire to bind or damage enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Cursed, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Summons chains covered in hellfire to bind or smash targets. Ego attack vs target. Success: regular Health damage; Fantastic success: grabbed and paralyzed. Subsequent rounds: Ego check vs Resilience for Health + Focus damage. Break free: Melee check target 20.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Hex Bolt</name><Description>Launches a magical bolt that can damage or curse a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Chaotic, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack vs Agility. Success: regular damage; Fantastic success: double damage + target trouble for one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Hit and Run</name><Description>Allows quick attack and disengage with minimal risk of reprisal.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack with edge. Success: regular damage + free movement up to half Run Speed. Fantastic success: double damage + weapon's special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Hit the Dirt</name><Description>Grants edge on dropping prone to avoid attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Keep Moving, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy attack on ally within earshot</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>All allies within earshot may fall prone to avoid attack. If ineligible, attack automatically fails.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Hurled Shield Bash</name><Description>Throws a shield at a target for damage or to knock them back.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield Bash, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces × rank</Range><Effect>Ranged attack on enemy. Success: regular damage; Fantastic success: double damage + knocked prone. Shield returns to character.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Hurled Shield Block</name><Description>Blocks incoming attacks while the shield is thrown.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield I, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy attacks ally's Agility</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>5 spaces × rank</Range><Effect>Ally gains Health Damage Reduction equal to character's Shield power. Shield returns to character.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Hurled Shield Deflection</name><Description>Deflects attacks using a thrown shield.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield Deflection, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy attacks ally's Agility</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>5 spaces × rank</Range><Effect>Enemy has trouble on the attack. Shield returns to character.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Iconic Weapon</name><Description>Summons or enhances a legendary weapon with extra effects.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>The character owns and uses a unique weapon (e.g., Mjolnir or Captain America's shield). Must be approved by Narrator. Can be taken multiple times with different weapons.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Icy Tendrils of Ikthalon</name><Description>Produces freezing tendrils to immobilize or damage targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>Ego check vs Agility. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + target paralyzed by ice.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Illumination</name><Description>Creates light to reveal hidden enemies or objects.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Illuminates an object/point in line of sight within 50 spaces. Bright light. Concentration can be maintained even if moving out of range/line of sight.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Images of Ikonn</name><Description>Generates illusory duplicates to confuse enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create one sound and sight illusion duplicate per rank of a known person. Duplicates move up to 10 spaces, can swap places, mimic attacks. Can see through illusions with double edge on Ego check.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer, Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Immovable</name><Description>Grants stability, making the character resistant to being moved or knocked down.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Knocked back or prone</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Reduce knockback by 1 space per point of Melee defense.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Information Upload</name><Description>Instantly transfers knowledge to oneself or allies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Transmit knowledge or labels to a target via telepathy. Label lasts until target sleeps. Almost instantaneous transmission of any other knowledge.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Inspiration</name><Description>Boosts morale, granting edge or bonuses to allies’ rolls.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Inspire an ally in earshot. Ally gains edge on all action checks until start of character's next turn.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Instant Replay</name><Description>Allows repeating an action or attack for improved effect.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Failed check</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Once per battle, make a second attempt at a failed check, replacing the first attempt.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Integrity</name><Description>Grants resistance to mental or moral manipulation.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Can use Logic defense against Ego attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Ego Defence Score; Logic Defence Score</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Invisibility</name><Description>Renders the character unseen by normal vision.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character becomes invisible. Edge on Agility checks to sneak, enemies have trouble on Vigilance checks. Moving objects harder to spot.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Jinx</name><Description>Causes bad luck or disadvantage to a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Chaotic, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs target's Ego. Success: target has trouble on all actions. Fantastic: target loses next standard action.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers, Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Jump 1</name><Description>Grants the ability to leap great distances.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Gain Jump movement mode equal to Run Speed. Can jump vertically and horizontally.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Jump Speed; Combat Run Speed,replace:Combat Jump Speed; Combat Run Speed</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers, Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Jump 2</name><Description>Further increases jump distance and height.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Jump 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Jump Speed = rank × Run Speed. Outside combat, move three times as fast.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Jump Speed; Combat Run Speed x Rank,calc:Jump Speed; Combat Run Speed x Rank x 3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers, Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Jump 3</name><Description>Maximizes jumping ability.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Jump 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Outside combat, jump up to 50× Jump Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Jump Speed; Combat Jump Speed x 50</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Keep Moving</name><Description>Grants edge on movement-based actions to avoid attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Ally in line of sight and earshot demoralized or stunned</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ends demoralized or stunned condition on ally.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Kill Zone</name><Description>Creates an area of concentrated attack for extra damage.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Covering Fire, Power:Headshot, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy starts moving in line of sight</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ranged attack. Success: normal damage; Fantastic: double damage. Each target affected once per round. Character regains reaction.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Leaping Leglock</name><Description>Allows a grapple or leg attack while jumping.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flying Double Kick, Power:Crushing Grip, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack. Success: grab + regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + grabbed and stunned 1 round. Both knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Leech Life</name><Description>Drains health from a target to heal the user.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack vs Resilience. Success: target takes Health damage, character heals half; Fantastic: character heals full Health damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Leg Sweep</name><Description>Tripping attack to knock down enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Fast Strikes, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack. Success: enemy takes regular damage and knocked prone; Fantastic: enemy stunned 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Levitation</name><Description>Allows hovering or floating off the ground.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Move through air in any direction at Run Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Lightning Actions</name><Description>Increases speed of actions in combat.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Gain one extra standard action + one extra reaction per turn. Can turn Marvel die to Fantastic success for initiative.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Machine Telepathy</name><Description>Reads or controls machines mentally.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Communicate telepathically with one machine at a time. Must have met or seen the machine. Can be verbal, visual, or complex info (e.g., location). Unlimited distance within same dimension. Logic checks may bypass security on complex machines.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Macrodimensional Travel</name><Description>Moves the character across large dimensional distances.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 4, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Grow enough to travel into the Macroverse, Overspace, or other enlarged space dimensions. Return to normal size at will. Time and space rules differ in these dimensions (e.g., 1 hour Macroverse ≈ 1 month regular universe).</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Memory Blip</name><Description>Erases or alters recent memories in a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Cause target to forget up to 1 hour of memories. Logic check vs target's Logic defense. Success: memories forgotten; Fantastic: target has trouble recovering memories. Target can try Logic check to recover if suspicious; Fantastic success reveals who did it.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Mental Punch</name><Description>A telepathic attack that damages the mind.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Melee attack vs target. Success: regular Focus damage; Fantastic: double Focus damage + target stunned 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Mental Shelter</name><Description>Protects the mind from intrusion or manipulation.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Uncanny I, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Extend mental defenses to protect chosen people within 5 spaces × rank. Protected targets gain Focus Damage Reduction equal to character's Uncanny power.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Microdimensional Travel</name><Description>Allows tiny, precise dimensional movement.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shrink 4, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Shrink enough to travel into subatomic realms. Return to normal size at will. Time and space rules differ in these realms. Useful for hiding, but little else of interest.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Mighty 1</name><Description>Grants a bonus to strength-based actions.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Treat character as 1 size larger for lifting, carrying, swinging, and throwing. +1 Melee damage multiplier, +1 bonus to non-attack Melee checks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Melee Dmg Multiplier;1,add:Melee Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Mighty 2</name><Description>Further increases strength and damage output.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mighty 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Treat character as 2 sizes larger for lifting, carrying, swinging, and throwing. +2 Melee damage multiplier, +2 bonus to non-attack Melee checks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Melee Dmg Multiplier;2,add:Melee Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Mighty 3</name><Description>Significantly boosts strength and related abilities.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mighty 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Treat character as 3 sizes larger for lifting, carrying, swinging, and throwing. +3 Melee damage multiplier, +3 bonus to non-attack Melee checks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Melee Dmg Multiplier;3,add:Melee Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Mighty 4</name><Description>Maximizes strength and power.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mighty 3, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Treat character as 4 sizes larger for lifting, carrying, swinging, and throwing. +4 Melee damage multiplier, +4 bonus to non-attack Melee checks.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Melee Dmg Multiplier;4,add:Melee Non-Combant Check;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Mind Interrogation</name><Description>Extracts information from a target’s mind.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Mind Reading, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Delve into a target's mind via telepathic link. Logic check vs Logic defense. Success: ask one simple question and get answer; Fantastic: get more complex information.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Mind Reading</name><Description>Reads surface thoughts of a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Read surface thoughts of a linked target. Logic check vs Logic defense. Success: surface thoughts; Fantastic: ask one simple question and get answer.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Mirage</name><Description>Creates a visual illusion to mislead enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create a full-sensory mirage affecting linked target. Mirage can be anything desired and move freely.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Mirror Images</name><Description>Generates illusory duplicates to confuse foes.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Animated Illusion, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create one sound and sight illusion duplicate per rank. Duplicates look and sound like character, under complete control. Move up to 10 spaces, swap places, mimic attacks. Hit removes duplicate; successful attack or reveal ends illusion.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Mists of Morpheus</name><Description>Envelops an area in sleep-inducing mist.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs Vigilance defense. Success: target stunned while concentrating; Fantastic: target falls asleep.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Mists of Munnopor</name><Description>A mystical fog that obscures vision and confuses targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create thick fog up to 100 spaces per rank. Blocks line of sight beyond 10 spaces. Prevents flying, gliding, or webslinging within fog.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Molecular Destabilization</name><Description>Destroys or weakens matter at a molecular level.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make a close attack against an object their size or smaller. Success: object explodes; targets within 2 spaces take regular damage. Fantastic success: double damage and ignore Health Damage Reduction.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Multiversal Portal</name><Description>Opens a gateway to another universe.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Multiversal Travel Together, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Opens a glowing portal next to character that moves anything entering it to a clear space in another universe previously visited. Can close at will. Portal is two-way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Multiversal Travel</name><Description>Allows the character to move between universes.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Instantly moves from one universe to another. Arrival location is a place they've been, or closest available corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Multiversal Travel Other</name><Description>Transports other targets across universes.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Multiversal Travel, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement, or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs target's Vigilance. Success: send target to another universe; target arrives in any previously visited location, otherwise closest corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Multiversal Travel Together</name><Description>Moves a group through the multiverse as one.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Multiversal Travel, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement, or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character moves to another universe, taking any touched target along. Arrival location is a place they've been or closest corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>On Your Feet</name><Description>Grants edge on standing up from prone or being knocked down.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Keep Moving, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Ally in line of sight and earshot is knocked prone</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>All prone allies within earshot immediately stand if able. Allies unable to stand are unaffected.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Operations Center</name><Description>Provides remote access to tactical or strategic information.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Combat Support, Power:Fire, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Inspire allies within earshot up to character's Vigilance defense. Affected allies gain edge on all action checks until next turn. Concentration breaks if character uses movement.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Orchestra of Overkill</name><Description>Coordinates multiple attacks or effects for maximum damage.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Dance Of Death, Power:Fast Hands, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Agility check vs all enemies within 10 spaces and line of sight. Success: half regular damage; Fantastic success: full damage + bleeding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Orders</name><Description>Issues commands to allies with bonus effect.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Command, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Give order to a target with telepathic link and no Focus. Logic check vs target's Logic defense. Success: target obeys; Fantastic: character gains edge next use on same target. Orders must be completable in ≤1 hour.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Partial Phase</name><Description>Allows partial intangibility to avoid attacks or obstacles.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make any portion of body and clothing tangible or intangible at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Penance Stare</name><Description>Inflicts psychic damage based on the target’s guilt.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Cursed</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack vs target within 3 spaces per rank. Success: Focus damage; Fantastic: double damage + target paralyzed 1 round. Heroic targets take half damage. Shattered targets recover either cleansed or emotionally drained, per Narrator.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Phase Object</name><Description>Makes an object intangible to pass through matter.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make any touched object intangible, up to rank sizes bigger than self. Includes attached or contained items.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Phase Other</name><Description>Renders another target intangible.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make any touched person and clothing intangible. Can include anyone they are touching. Phasing ends if contact broken. Objects disrupted may damage phased targets.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Phase Self</name><Description>Makes oneself intangible to avoid attacks or pass through objects.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character and clothing become intangible. Can move through anything. Cannot affect or be affected by non-phased objects.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Phase Walk</name><Description>Allows phased movement through obstacles or walls.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Move freely through anything while phasing, at Run Speed. Can carry anything phasing with them.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Point-Blank Parry</name><Description>Grants edge when parrying attacks at close range.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy within 2 spaces misses attack</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make ranged attack against enemy. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + bleeding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Possess Vehicle</name><Description>Takes control of a vehicle temporarily.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Cursed, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Take magical control of vehicle touched. Hellfire engulfs vehicle (no damage). Anyone contacting vehicle takes damage equal to rank. Fantastic: regular Health + Focus damage. Vehicle speed doubles, can climb walls and jump. Use Ego for checks with edge.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Possession</name><Description>Temporarily controls another creature or person.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Cursed, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs target's Ego defense. Success: take over target's body completely. Target can attempt Ego check to end possession. Heroic tag gives edges on checks. Harmful actions may trigger additional checks.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Powerful Hex</name><Description>Curses a target with a strong detrimental effect.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Chaotic, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Varies</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Cast hex to use any other power of qualifying rank regardless of prerequisites. Pay regular Focus cost +5. Permanent powers count as Concentration; numbered permanent powers multiply Focus cost by number (e.g., Mighty 3 = 15 Focus).</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Probability-Manipulation Hex</name><Description>Alters the likelihood of events for a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Chaotic, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>When ally within 5 spaces × rank attempts a check with trouble, eliminates trouble and grants edge instead.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Protection Hex</name><Description>Grants defensive magical protection to a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Chaotic, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Produce hex to protect self. Make Ego check; result becomes defense against attacks. Can retry. Fantastic: grants Health Damage Reduction 1.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Phasing</PowerSet><name>Quick Phase</name><Description>Phase through objects or obstacles rapidly.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Phase Self, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character and clothing instantly become intangible.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Quick Toss</name><Description>Throws an object with extra speed and accuracy.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Crushing Grip, Power:Mighty 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>Grabbed target</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Throw grabbed person at target. Range depends on Mighty level and size. Ranged attack against target: failure damages thrown person; success damages target; Fantastic knocks target prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Rally on Me</name><Description>Boosts allies’ morale or restores edge when nearby.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:On Your Feet, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Allies in earshot (up to Vigilance number) can move toward character at half speed. If within reach after move, recover Focus = 5 × character rank. Can use once per battle.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Regain Focus</name><Description>Recover spent edge or regain composure.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Unflappable Poise, Power:Untouchable Position, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Recover Focus equal to character's Vigilance.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Reinforced Skeleton</name><Description>Bones are stronger, reducing damage from impacts.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character gains Health Damage Reduction 1.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Resize Object</name><Description>Changes the size of a target object.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 2 or Shrink 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Change size of any object within reach. Resize limits follow character's Grow or Shrink powers.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Resize Other</name><Description>Alters the size of a target creature or object.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grow 2 or Shrink 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Resize any person and their clothing within touch, up to character's Grow or Shrink limits. Must grab unwilling targets first.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Return Fire</name><Description>Immediately responds to an attack with counterfire.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Suppressive Fire, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy declares attack against character</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Agility attack vs target's Vigilance defense. Success: damage bypasses Health DR, applied to Focus. Fantastic: double damage, target stunned 1 round if Focus damaged.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Reverse Punch</name><Description>A punch that uses an opponent’s momentum against them.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flexible Bones 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack on enemy with edge. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + stun 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Reverse-Momentum Throw</name><Description>Throws an enemy using their own force to increase damage.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Defense Stance, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>While Defense Stance active, a close attack against character misses</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Attacker is knocked prone and takes half the damage their attack would have dealt.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Rico-Shield</name><Description>Throws a shield that ricochets between targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Hurled Shield Bash, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces × character's rank</Range><Effect>Ranged attack on target. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: target knocked prone and chain attack on next target. Shield returns to character after all attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Riposte</name><Description>Counters an opponent’s attack with an immediate strike.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy makes close attack that fails</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack on enemy. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + weapon special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Rubberneck</name><Description>Increases flexibility of the neck and head to avoid attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Flexible Bones 1, Power:Extended Reach 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Move head away from body up to reach to establish line of sight.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Run on Water</name><Description>Grants the ability to move across water surfaces.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Feet skip across water. Continuous running prevents sinking.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Tactics</PowerSet><name>Scatter</name><Description>Disperses effects or attacks across multiple targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Hit the Dirt, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy in line of sight declares attack on ally within earshot</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Allies in earshot (up to character rank) move away at half speed and fall prone. If this prevents initial attack from hitting, attack fails automatically.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Sense Sins</name><Description>Detects moral wrongdoing in a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Cursed</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs target's Ego defense. Success: sense past horrible deeds. Fantastic: sense immediate intended actions.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Sense Supernatural</name><Description>Detects mystical or supernatural phenomena.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Sense supernatural entities within 100 spaces × rank. Location and general status revealed. Ego check vs Vigilance if targets wish to remain hidden. Fantastic: identify if cursed or demonic.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Shape-Shift</name><Description>Alters physical form into another creature or object.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Disguise, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Change into another form no more than one size larger/smaller. Gains natural abilities of form (e.g., flying as bird, breathing underwater as fish).</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield</name><Description>Provides a basic defensive barrier.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character gains Health Damage Reduction 1.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield 2</name><Description>Improved defensive barrier with extra protection.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character gains Health Damage Reduction 2.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield 3</name><Description>Further enhancement to protective shielding.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character gains Health Damage Reduction 3.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield 4</name><Description>Maximizes defensive shielding capabilities.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shield 3, Rank:6</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>25 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character gains Health Damage Reduction 4.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield Bash</name><Description>Uses a shield to attack and potentially knock down an enemy.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack on enemy within reach. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage and target knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield Deflection</name><Description>Deflects incoming attacks using a shield.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is target of attack against Agility defense</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Attack has trouble.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Shield of the Seraphim</name><Description>A powerful, mystical shield that offers superior defense.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Magical shield protects from physical damage. Attacks ≤20 damage absorbed; attacks >20 destroy shield. Character unharmed either way.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Shield Bearer</PowerSet><name>Shield Wall</name><Description>Creates a barrier with allies for group defense.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Brace for Impact, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Attacks against character have trouble. Breaks concentration if character moves.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Shrink 1</name><Description>Reduces size slightly, gaining edge on stealth or avoidance.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character can shrink to little size; return to normal at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Shrink 2</name><Description>Further reduces size and increases stealth advantages.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shrink 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character can shrink to tiny size; return to normal at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Shrink 3</name><Description>Significantly shrinks, gaining greater evasion and small-object access.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shrink 2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character can shrink to miniature size; return to normal at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Shrink 4</name><Description>Maximizes size reduction for extreme stealth and maneuvering.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shrink 3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character can shrink to microscopic size; return to normal at will.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Resize</PowerSet><name>Shrinking Dodge</name><Description>Improves evasion when small or reduced in size.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Shrink 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Attacker has trouble on attack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Shut Down Powers</name><Description>Temporarily disables a target’s powers.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Dampen Power, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack on target within 20 spaces. Success: removes all target powers. Must pay highest cost or minimum 15 Focus.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Silence Area</name><Description>Suppresses sound in a defined area.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Illumination, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Area (5 spaces × rank, within 50 spaces) becomes silent. Cannot hear inside/outside. Must stay within 50 spaces to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Silence Self</name><Description>Suppresses one’s own sound to avoid detection.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Illumination, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character makes no noise unless desired. Edge on Agility to sneak; enemies have trouble perceiving them.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Slip Free</name><Description>Grants edge to escape grapples or restraints.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character is grabbed or pinned</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Character cannot be grabbed or pinned.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Slow-Motion Dodge</name><Description>React in slow-motion to avoid attacks with edge.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Enemy attacks character's Agility defense</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Enemy has trouble on attack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Slow-Motion Shoot-Dodge</name><Description>Combine movement and attack while avoiding hits.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Slow-Motion Dodge, Power:Weapons Blazing, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant, 1 round</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Split ranged attack on two targets or focus one. Success: half damage; Fantastic: full damage + bonus attack. Character hovers midair, attacks against Agility have trouble until next turn, then falls prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Smash</name><Description>Delivers a powerful strike to cause extra damage.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Clobber, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack with edge. Add +1 Melee damage per 2 Focus spent. Success: normal damage; Fantastic: double damage and stun 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Snap Shooting</name><Description>Fires quickly with edge on accuracy.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Split ranged attack on two targets or focus one. Success: half damage; Fantastic: full damage + target bleeding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Sniping</name><Description>Long-range attacks with precision bonus.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ranged attack on enemy ≥20 spaces away. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: triple damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Speed Blast</name><Description>Boosts movement speed for rapid action.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 2, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10</Range><Effect>Ranged attack. Success: target stunned 1 round; Fantastic: target stunned, character knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Speed Run 1</name><Description>Grants high-speed movement temporarily.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Multiply Run Speed by rank. Outside combat: move 3× faster.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Run Speed; Combat Run Speed x Rank, calc: Run Speed; Combat Run Speed x 3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Speed Run 2</name><Description>Further increases running speed and maneuverability.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Speed Run 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Outside combat, move up to 50× increased Run Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc: Run Speed; Combat Run Speed x 50</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Speed</PowerSet><name>Speed Swim</name><Description>Allows faster movement in water.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Multiply Swim Speed by rank. Outside combat: move 3× faster.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Swim Speed; Combat Run Speed x Rank, calc: Swim Speed: Combat Run Speed x Rank x 3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Spider-Dodge</name><Description>Improves reflexive evasion, especially acrobatic.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Agility attack against character</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Attacker has trouble. If attack misses, character may leap at Jump Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Spider-Pheromones</name><Description>Emits pheromones that attract or repel.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>5 spaces</Range><Effect>Edge on Ego (Intimidation) vs people not attracted to character’s gender; Edge on Ego (Persuasion) vs attracted people.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Spider-Sense</name><Description>Warns of danger through heightened perception.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Edge on initiative and Vigilance. Enemies have trouble on Agility attacks vs Vigilance. Permanent bonus to Agility defense.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Spider-Strike</name><Description>Acrobatic attack that gains edge from mobility.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Split close attack on two targets or focus one. Success: half damage; Fantastic: full damage + paralyzed by webbing. After attack: free half-speed run, jump, or climb.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Spin-Throw</name><Description>Uses spinning motion to throw an enemy or object with added force.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Grappling Technique, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Grabbed enemy within reach</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Melee attack. Success: regular damage + knock prone; Fantastic: double damage, prone, pinned, stunned 1 round. Enemy can be moved within reach.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Illusion</PowerSet><name>Static Illusion</name><Description>Creates an immobile visual illusion to distract.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Illumination</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create visual-only static illusion within line of sight, 50 spaces. Max size: 3× character. Concentration breaks if moving beyond 50 spaces or losing line of sight.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Steal Powers</name><Description>Temporarily gains abilities from another target.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Clone Powers, Power:Shut Down Powers, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>15+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack on grabbed target. Success: remove all target powers and take them for self. Must pay cost of powers (or min 15 Focus). Costs for using powers are paid normally.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Plasticity</PowerSet><name>Stilt Steps</name><Description>Increase height and stride for movement or reach.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Extended Reach 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Run Speed and Climb Speed double for this movement.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Stopping Power</name><Description>Improves ability to halt or resist movement or attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Double Tap, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ranged attack. Success: regular damage; Fantastic: double damage + another regular attack on same target.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Sturdy 1</name><Description>Grants resistance to damage or knockback.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 1</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Sturdy 2</name><Description>Further improves durability.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Sturdy 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 2</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;2</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Sturdy 3</name><Description>Significantly increases resilience.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Sturdy 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 3</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Sturdy 4</name><Description>Maximizes toughness and damage resistance.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Sturdy 3, Rank:6</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Health Damage Reduction 4</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Health Dmg Reduction;4</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Summon Portal</name><Description>Opens a portal to another location or dimension.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Opens a glowing portal between two locations in the Multiverse. Anything can move through until closed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Elemental Control</PowerSet><name>Supernova</name><Description>Generates a massive burst of energy to damage multiple targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Elemental Blast, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack against all enemies within 10 spaces; success = half damage, Fantastic success = full damage + elemental effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Suppressive Fire</name><Description>Continuous ranged attacks to keep enemies at bay.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Agility attack against target's Vigilance; damage to target's Focus on success, double Focus damage + stun on Fantastic success.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Swipe Power</name><Description>Sweeping attack that affects multiple targets.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Copy Powers, Power:Dampen Power, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10+ Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Remove one of target's powers and take it for own use.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Attack</name><Description>Uses telekinesis to strike or damage a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Manipulation, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>5 spaces × Rank</Range><Effect>Logic attack against target's Melee defense; success = regular damage, Fantastic success = double + stun 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Barrier</name><Description>Creates a defensive barrier using telekinesis.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Grab, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Creates invisible barrier; controls target placement and absorbs attacks ≤10 damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Crush</name><Description>Crushes objects or enemies with telekinetic force.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Grab, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Logic attack vs grabbed target's Resilience; success = regular damage, Fantastic = double + pinned.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Grab</name><Description>Grabs and holds objects or enemies telekinetically.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Manipulation, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>5 spaces × Rank</Range><Effect>Logic attack to grab target; Fantastic success also pins target.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Manipulation</name><Description>Manipulates multiple objects or targets at once.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>5 spaces × Rank</Range><Effect>Manipulate objects in line of sight; Logic vs Agility if resisted.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Protection</name><Description>Enhances defenses using telekinetic force.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Barrier, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Personal telekinetic shield absorbs attacks ≤10 damage; destroyed if >10, but user unharmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Protection 2</name><Description>Improved telekinetic shielding.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Protection 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Telekinetic shield absorbs ≤20 damage; destroyed if more, user unharmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Protection 3</name><Description>Further strengthens telekinetic defenses.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Protection 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Telekinetic shield absorbs ≤30 damage; destroyed if more, user unharmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Protection Z</name><Description>Maximizes telekinetic defensive capabilities.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Protection 3, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Telekinetic shield absorbs ≤40 damage; destroyed if more, user unharmed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Reinforcement</name><Description>Boosts strength or durability of objects or allies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Protection 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Telekinetic shield user attacked</Trigger><Cost>Varies</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Damage that gets through telekinetic protection is applied to Focus instead, leaving shield intact.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Sphere</name><Description>Creates a floating protective or offensive sphere.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Protection 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacked or in danger</Trigger><Cost>Same as Telekinetic Protection</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Protective sphere envelops self and allies; can move unwanted enemies outside; absorbs attacks like Telekinetic Protection.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telekinesis</PowerSet><name>Telekinetic Toss</name><Description>Throws objects with telekinetic force.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telekinetic Grab, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>5 spaces × Rank</Range><Effect>Throw a grabbed target at another target; Logic vs Agility; success = regular damage, Fantastic = target knocked prone.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Telepathic Blast</name><Description>Damages or disrupts targets mentally.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Logic attack vs target in line of sight; success = regular Focus damage, Fantastic = double + stun 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Telepathic Link</name><Description>Establishes a mental link between allies.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Telepathic communication with one person met or seen before; Logic vs Vigilance to force if target resists.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Telepathic Network</name><Description>Connects multiple minds for coordinated action.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Telepathic Link, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>None</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Telepathic communication with group up to 5 per rank, as long as everyone met or seen before.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Telepathic Possession</name><Description>Temporarily controls a target mentally.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Orders, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Possess a target with established Telepathic Link who has no Focus. Logic check vs target's Logic. Can permanently transfer mind into empty-minded targets.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport 1</name><Description>Allows short-range teleportation.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Blink</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Teleport into a clear space up to 10×Rank spaces; outside combat 100×Rank.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Teleport Speed;Rank x 10, calc:Teleport Speed;Rank x 100</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport 2</name><Description>Improves teleportation distance and accuracy.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 1</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Outside combat, teleport up to 1,000×Rank spaces.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Teleport Speed;Rank x 1000</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport Blind</name><Description>Teleports without needing line of sight.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Teleport to a location never seen before, up to 10×Rank spaces; outside combat 100×Rank. Teleporting into solids causes damage and possible trapping.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport Object</name><Description>Teleports objects to a target location.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Teleport an object within reach along with self. Object can be up to Rank sizes bigger than character.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport Other</name><Description>Transports another person or creature.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 2, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Make Ego check vs target's Vigilance to teleport target; colliding with solid material causes damage and possible trapping.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleport Together</name><Description>Teleports a group of allies simultaneously.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Teleport self and any touched allies up to 10×Rank spaces; outside combat 100×Rank. Must grab unwilling targets first.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Teleportal</name><Description>Creates a fixed portal for repeated travel.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport 1, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Open a glowing portal linking two spaces, up to 10×Rank in combat, 1,000×Rank outside combat. Anything can pass until closed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Thunder</name><Description>Generates a loud, damaging sonic effect.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego check vs Resilience of all targets within 10 spaces. Success = deafened; Fantastic = deafened + stunned 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time-Out</name><Description>Pauses or slows time for a target briefly.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Instant Replay, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round per Rank</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character or ally is attacked</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Freeze time for self, act normally while everyone else appears frozen.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time-Out Bubble</name><Description>Creates an area where time is slowed or stopped.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Time-Out, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round per Rank</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character or ally is attacked</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create a time bubble affecting self and allies within 1×Rank spaces; act normally while others are frozen.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time-Out Tag</name><Description>Applies brief temporal effects on targets within range.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Time-Out, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>1 round per Rank</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character or ally is attacked</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Freeze time for one target within reach. Must grab unwilling target first.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time Portal</name><Description>Opens a gateway through time.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Time Travel Together, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Open a time portal connecting two periods in a clear location; anything can move through until closed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time Travel</name><Description>Moves the character through time themselves.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Movement</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Instantly move from current time to another; arrive at known location or closest corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time Travel Other</name><Description>Transports others through time.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Time Travel, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Send grabbed target to another time. Must be a known location or closest corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Omniversal Travel</PowerSet><name>Time Travel Together</name><Description>Allows a group to travel through time as one.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Time Travel, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard, Movement or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Target is grabbed</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Move to another time taking any touched person with self; must grab unwilling targets first. Arrive at known location or closest corresponding space.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Uncanny 1</name><Description>Grants minor edge to avoid danger or react unusually.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Reduce any damage multiplier against Focus by 1. Apply Tech Reliance if removable.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Focus Dmg Reduction;1</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Uncanny 2</name><Description>Improves uncanny reflexes or luck.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Uncanny 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Reduce any damage multiplier against Focus by 2.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Focus Dmg Reduction;2</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Uncanny 3</name><Description>Significantly increases chances of avoiding danger.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Uncanny 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Reduce any damage multiplier against Focus by 3.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Focus Dmg Reduction;3</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Uncanny 4</name><Description>Maximizes uncanny avoidance and reaction capabilities.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Uncanny 3, Rank:6</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Reduce any damage multiplier against Focus by 4.</Effect><statAdjust>replace:Focus Dmg Reduction;4</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Unflappable Poise</name><Description>Grants composure under pressure, resisting mental effects.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Defense Stance, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attacks have trouble; double trouble while using Defense Stance.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Super-Strength</PowerSet><name>Unrelenting Smash</name><Description>Delivers repeated powerful strikes in succession.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Ground-shaking Stomp, Power:Mighty 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Melee attack vs all enemies in reach; success = half damage, Fantastic = full damage + prone. Can repeat paying 15 Focus per extra attack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Unstoppable Assault</name><Description>Increases damage and edge on continuous attacks.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Furious Attacks, Power:Focused Fury, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Melee check vs all enemies in reach. Success = half damage; Fantastic = full damage + weapon special effect. Can repeat paying 15 Focus and moving up to half Speed. Each target affected once per round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Martial Arts</PowerSet><name>Untouchable Position</name><Description>Grants edge to avoid being hit or grappled.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Counterstrike Technique, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Other close attacks against character have trouble until start of next turn.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Vapors of Valtorr</name><Description>Emits damaging or obscuring mystical vapors.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Create inky mist up to 25 spaces per rank; blocks line of sight beyond 5 spaces. Later turns can attack one target per turn, Ego check vs Vigilance. Success = regular damage; Fantastic = double damage + blind 1 turn.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Venom Blast</name><Description>Projects venomous energy to damage or poison targets.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>5 spaces</Range><Effect>Ranged attack; Success = regular damage; Fantastic = double damage + stunned 1 round if damage dealt.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Vicious Attack</name><Description>Enhances attack damage and effectiveness.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Close attack; Success = regular damage; Fantastic = double damage + weapon special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Wallcrawling</name><Description>Allows climbing on walls and ceilings with ease.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Climb at speed equal to regular speed; never lose grip under normal conditions.</Effect><statAdjust>replace: Climb Speed; Run Speed</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Ranged Weapons</PowerSet><name>Weapons Blazing</name><Description>Grants edge when using multiple weapons simultaneously.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Snap Shooting</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Split attack for two ranged attacks against separate targets or focus single target. Agility check vs targets. Success = half damage; Fantastic = full damage + bonus attack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Weather Chill</name><Description>Manipulates cold weather to hinder or damage enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Lower temperature in area ~1 mile across to 0°F.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Weather Control</PowerSet><name>Weather Warm</name><Description>Manipulates heat to aid or damage targets.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Raise temperature in area ~1 mile across to 1000°F.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Webcasting</name><Description>Projects web-like energy for offense or support.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>Ranged attack; Success = paralyze target; Fantastic = pin target. Break free: Melee check TN 20.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Webgliding</name><Description>Allows gliding using web lines.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Webcasting, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Gain Glide movement mode at double Run Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>calc:Combat Glide Speed;2 x Combat Run Speed,replace;Glide Speed;Combat Glide Speed</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Webgrabbing</name><Description>Captures or restrains targets with webs.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Webcasting, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>Ranged attack; Success = grab target; Fantastic = grab + pin. Break free: Melee check TN 20.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Webslinging</name><Description>Swing or traverse using web lines.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Webcasting, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Gain swingline movement mode at triple Run Speed. Reach = Swingline Speed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Webtrapping</name><Description>Sets web traps to immobilize enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Webgrabbing, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Rank × 15 minutes</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Fill up to 5 spaces with sticky webs. Spaces = difficult terrain. Creatures in spaces must make Agility check TN 20 or be paralyzed. Break free: Melee check TN 20.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Melee Weapons</PowerSet><name>Whirling Frenzy</name><Description>Spin attack that hits multiple enemies.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Fast Attacks, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Agility check vs all enemies in reach. Success = half damage; Fantastic = full damage + weapon special effect.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Magic</PowerSet><name>Winds of Watoomb (Sorcery Set)</name><Description>Generates mystical wind effects for attack or movement.</Description><PreRequisites>Tag:Sorcerous, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or Reaction</Action><Trigger>Damage gets through Shield of the Seraphim</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Conjure swirling winds; halve foe movement within 10 spaces per Rank. Can push away smoke/mist: Ego check vs opposing controller; success ends effect; Fantastic knocks prone. Can transfer damage through Shield of Seraphim to Focus instead.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Wisdom</name><Description>Grants insight or edge on knowledge-based checks.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>None</Action><Trigger>None</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Use Ego defense against Logic attacks.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Basic</PowerSet><name>Wisecracker</name><Description>Uses humor or cleverness to distract or undermine foes.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Reaction</Action><Trigger>Character succeeds in attack on enemy in earshot, or enemy fails attack in earshot</Trigger><Cost>None</Cost><Range>None</Range><Effect>Ego attack on enemy; Success = regular Focus damage; Fantastic = double Focus damage + target stunned 1 round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Charmed Life</name><Description>The character seems like they were born lucky.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>none</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>The character gains an edge on any single action check each round. This does not stack with any other edges.</Effect><statAdjust>replace: Logic Defence Score: Ego Defence Score</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Telepathy</PowerSet><name>Copy Psyche</name><Description>The character can move whole minds around.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Information Upload, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Copy the mind of a linked person and store in own mind; rules for storing, removing, and interacting with extra minds.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Cosmic Awareness</name><Description>The character can detect details about things anywhere in the universe.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Microscopic Awareness, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>Unlimited</Range><Effect>Sense selected things at any distance in the same universe; includes location, velocity, and status of known items, creatures, or groups.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Cure-All</name><Description>The character can cure what ails—mostly.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Healing Hands, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Cures most temporary ailments on touch (Ego vs TN 12). Fantastic success recovers health/focus. Only affects acute, not chronic/permanent, conditions.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Danger Sense</name><Description>The character can feel danger on the way.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Precognition 1, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>none</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Character gets a turn during the bonus round of any combat, even without a fantastic initiative result.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Detect Supers</name><Description>The character can sense super-powered people.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Can sense anyone with superpowers within a certain distance. Reveals count/direction/distance. Range 5 miles (general)/25 miles (single origin). Powers from Special Training origin not detected.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Evil Eye</name><Description>The character can inflict trouble on those who cross their path.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Jinx You, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>5 spaces per rank</Range><Effect>Target has trouble on all action checks for the duration. No range limit after activation. Focus spent each turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Healing Hands</name><Description>The character has a healing touch.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Let's GO, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 or more Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Heals a target with a touch; each Focus spent restores 1 Health. Minimum 10 Focus. Cannot heal beyond max Health.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Intuition</name><Description>The character has a bad feeling about this.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Player gets an idea from the Narrator about which choice would be best for them in the long run.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Jinx You</name><Description>The character can hit you with a jinx.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>On successful Melee check, target has trouble on all action checks for duration; fantastic success also deals Melee damage. Focus spent each turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Jinx You All</name><Description>The character can jinx a whole group of foes at once.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Evil Eye, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>5 spaces per rank</Range><Effect>Picks up to one foe per rank; those foes have trouble on all action checks for duration. No range limit after activation. Focus spent each turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Let's Go</name><Description>The character can get a friend back on their feet.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The target is knocked unconscious.</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Eliminates effects of a target losing all Health; target remains awake and mobile but can only use movement; does not prevent death; target falls unconscious if Health ≤0 when effect ends or Health increases above 0.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Lucky Me</name><Description>Things are about to go the character's way.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>The character gains an edge on all action checks while power is in effect. Focus cost paid each turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Lucky Us</name><Description>The character can share their good fortune with many friends.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Wish You Luck, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>5 spaces per rank</Range><Effect>Picks up to one ally per rank in line of sight, self and allies gain edge on all action checks; no range limit after activation; Focus cost maintained per turn.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Lucky You</name><Description>The character can give good fortune to a friend.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Lucky Me, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Touches an ally; that ally gains edge on all action checks for duration; Focus cost per turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Microscopic Awareness</name><Description>The character can detect details about the smallest things.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>I space per rank</Range><Effect>See/identify items normally requiring microscope (e.g., fingerprints, hair, DNA); can identify/link DNA to relatives.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Never Surrender</name><Description>The character can help a friend rally.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Removes effects of losing all Focus; target isn't demoralized/loses 'trouble' penalty, can't spend more Focus, can be shattered. Power ends if Focus >0. If still 0 Focus at end, target becomes demoralized.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Postcognition 1</name><Description>The character knows what just happened.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Sense what happened to a person/place/item within reach in last 6 hours, using target's senses. Can review events, 'fast-forward'/'rewind' time period.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Postcognition 2</name><Description>The character knows what happened in the day.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Postcognition 1, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Sense what happened to a person/place/item within reach in last 24 hours; otherwise works as Postcognition 1.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Postcognition 3</name><Description>The character knows what happened in the year.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Postcognition 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Sense what happened to a person/place/item within reach in any 6-hour period in last year; otherwise as Postcognition 1.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Postcognition 4</name><Description>The character knows what happened in the past century.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Postcognition 3, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Sense what happened to a person/place/item within reach in any week-long period in past century; otherwise as Postcognition 1.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Precognition 1</name><Description>The character can see the near future.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Intuition, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Gains sense of what will happen to person/place/item in next 24 hours; player may ask 1 question about day ahead and get an honest, short answer; predictions not guaranteed.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Precognition 2</name><Description>The character can see the week ahead.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Precognition I, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Gains sense of what will happen to a person/place/item within reach in next week; can also consider fate of something within a mile over next 24 hours; otherwise works as Precognition I.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Precognition 3</name><Description>The character can see the month ahead.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Precognition 2, Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>15 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Gains sense of what will happen to a person/place/item within reach in next month; alternatively can consider fate of something within a mile over next week or within 100 miles over next 24 hours; otherwise as Precognition I.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Sixth Sense</PowerSet><name>Precognition 4</name><Description>The character can see a whole year ahead.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Precognition 3, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Gains sense of what will happen to a person/place/item within reach in next year; alternative ranges and time frames described; otherwise works as Precognition I.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Razorwebs</name><Description>The character's webbing can cut!</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Webcasting</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>10 spaces</Range><Effect>Agility attack on enemy; success deals Health damage; fantastic success adds bleeding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Real Jinx</name><Description>The character is bad luck for their foes.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:4</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>none</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>All direct-action attackers have trouble on their action checks; does not stack with other trouble.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Repulse</name><Description>The character can force things away.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Stick Around, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>none</Duration><Action>Standard, movement or reaction</Action><Trigger>Attacks the character</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>1 space</Range><Effect>Can force something touching or nearly touching away like Stick Around power; targets resisting must pass Melee vs TN 16; can shove attackers, propel self, keep objects hovering (max height 1 space), or add distance to jumps.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Restore</name><Description>The character can heal a shattered mind.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Soothing Touch, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>20 Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>On Ego vs TN 20 check success, target restored to 1 Focus; fantastic success restores full Focus; user reduced to 1 Focus after any success; failure still pays 20 Focus.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Resurrect</name><Description>The character can help someone defy death.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Healing Hands, Rank:5</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>20 or more Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Makes Ego vs TN (10 + hours dead) action check; success restores target to 1 Health; fantastic success full Health; user reduced to 1 Focus after success; can only resurrect relatively intact bodies soon after death.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Soothing Touch</name><Description>The character can help get a friend's head back in the game.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Never Surrender, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 or more Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Restores target's Focus by spending Focus; minimum 10 Focus must be spent; cannot exceed target's max Focus; excess Focus lost.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Stick Around</name><Description>The character can make things stick together.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Wallcrawling, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>Someone attempts to move or move another within power's range</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>1 space per rank</Range><Effect>Sticks two things together like Wallcrawling; breaking requires Melee vs TN 16; can end at will. Creative uses include sticking people, doors, or objects.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Telespot</name><Description>The character can create small teleportals.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Teleport I, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>10 spaces per rank</Range><Effect>Deploys small teleportals to attack/affect items within 10x rank; as reaction can deflect or redirect attacks with Agility check; effects vary by success.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Venom Bash</name><Description>Charges up fist for bioelectric punch.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Barehanded Melee attack; success deals Health damage; fantastic success doubles damage and stuns target one round.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Venom Burst</name><Description>Massive bioelectric charge.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Venom Bash, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Melee check vs foes within 5 spaces; success knocks prone; fantastic success also does half Health damage.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Spider-Powers</PowerSet><name>Venom Sword</name><Description>Creates a sword of bioelectricity.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Venom Blast, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>Character or ally within reach attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per round</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Sword adds +2 Melee damage multiplier; fantastic success doubles damage and stuns. Bonuses don’t stack.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Luck</PowerSet><name>Wish You Luck</name><Description>Makes a friend lucky even from across the room.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Lucky You, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus per turn</Cost><Range>5 spaces per rank</Range><Effect>Ally in line of sight gains edge on all action checks; no range limit after activation; Focus cost per turn to maintain.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Detect Lie</name><Description>The character can identify if others are telling the truth.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Understand Body Language, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>Verbal communication</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Can make Ego check vs communicator's defense; success reveals if lying, fantastic success reveals why; only works if communicator knows they are lying.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Healing</PowerSet><name>Healing Hands</name><Description>The character has a healing touch.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Let's GO, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>10 or more Focus</Cost><Range>Reach</Range><Effect>Heals target by spending Focus; minimum 10 Focus; cannot exceed max Health; excess lost.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Indecipherable</name><Description>The character has a unique internal language.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Understand Spoken Language, Power:Understand Unusual Communication, Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>none</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Character thinks and communicates in own internal language, immune to telepathic powers like Mind Reading or Mind Interrogation.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Power Slider</name><Description>The character's power strength waxes and wanes based on vital criteria.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Permanent</Duration><Action>none</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Powers boosted or dampened depending on chosen criteria (confidence, faith, media popularity); boosts/dampens affect areas, durations, damage multipliers and Fantastic success effects for the duration of a combat or day.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Swap Items</name><Description>The character swaps items with someone.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Swap Places</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Swaps possessions with another person within 2 spaces per rank; must make Ego check if target unwilling; swapped items return when effect ends.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Swap Places</name><Description>The character swaps places with someone.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Swaps places with target within 2 spaces per rank; Ego check if target unwilling; swaps back when effect ends.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Power Control</PowerSet><name>Swap Powers</name><Description>The character swaps powers with a target.</Description><PreRequisites>Rank:3</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>10 or more Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Swaps all non-swap powers with target within 2 spaces per rank; must pay highest cost or minimum 10 Focus; can use new powers normally; pay any cost when using swapped powers.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Teleportation</PowerSet><name>Swap Status</name><Description>The character swaps status with someone.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Swap Items, Rank:2</PreRequisites><Duration>Concentration</Duration><Action>Standard or reaction</Action><Trigger>The character is attacked</Trigger><Cost>5 Focus</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Swaps entire or selective status with target within 2 spaces per rank; includes Lost Health, Focus, conditions, Occupations, Traits, Tags; careful as can cause deaths or shattering.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Body Language</name><Description>The character can read body language.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>At first encounter with culture, Logic vs TN 13 check to learn body language; edge if language known; success allows understanding/emulation; fantastic success permanent understanding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Code</name><Description>The character can figure out any code.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Understand Written Language</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Logic vs TN 13 check on first encounter with code; edge if related language known; success allows understanding and communication; fantastic success permanent understanding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Sign Language</name><Description>The character can understand sign language.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Logic vs TN 13 check on first encounter with sign language; edge if related language known; success allows understanding and signing; fantastic success permanent understanding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Spoken Language</name><Description>The character can understand spoken language.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Logic vs TN 13 check on first encounter with spoken language; edge if related language known; success allows understanding and speaking; fantastic success permanent understanding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Unusual Communication</name><Description>The character can understand other communication forms.</Description><PreRequisites>Power:Understand Body Language</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Logic vs TN 13 check on first encounter with unusual communication (not hearing, vision, or code); edge if known; success allows use; fantastic success permanent understanding; includes scent, touch, taste, etc.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
<Power><PowerSet>Translation</PowerSet><name>Understand Written Language</name><Description>The character can understand written language.</Description><PreRequisites>None</PreRequisites><Duration>Instant</Duration><Action>Standard</Action><Trigger>none</Trigger><Cost>none</Cost><Range>none</Range><Effect>Logic vs TN 13 check on first encounter with written language; edge if related language known; success allows reading and writing; fantastic success permanent understanding.</Effect><statAdjust>None</statAdjust></Power>
</Powers>